A Register of the John K. Cooley papers, 1952-2008
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs, 1958-1990 (Box 11-12)
  - Photographs collected by John Cooley, 1958-1990 (Folder 11)
    - Ayatollah Khomeini with his family in Iran, prior to exile, 1958 (gift of Chris Isham, ABC News) (Folder 11: 7)
    - Ayatollah Khomeini with Ayatollah Morteza Pasindideh, 1979 (gift of Chris Isham, ABC News) (Folder 11: 8)
    - Suez Canal, with President Anwar Sadat, General Hosni Mubarak, and Prince Reza Pahlavi, 1979 (copyright, Annie Jennings) (Folder 11: 9)
    - Beirut and Lebanon, United Press International photographs, by Claude Salhani, 1981-1984 (80 prints, 2 folders) (Folder 11: 10-11)
  - Photographs taken by John K. Cooley, 1966-1983 (Folder 12)
    - Military parade in unidentified country, possibly Algeria, undated (37 prints and negatives) (Folder 12: 1)
    - Various photographs, Saudi Arabia and Bahrain, undated (7 prints, 7 slides) (Folder 12: 2)
    - Yemen, 1967 (31 prints) (Folder 12: 3)
    - Western Sahara, 1969 (22 prints) (Folder 12: 4)
    - Photos taken on assignment with Christian Science Monitor, 1966-1980 (33 prints) (Folder 12: 5)
    - Izmir, Turkey, 1979 (10 prints, 3 contact sheets) (Folder 12: 6)
    - Libya and Moammar Qadaffi, undated, probably 1980s (65 color prints) (Folder 12: 7)
    - South Lebanon and Israel, May-June 1983 (Folder 12: 8)
- Assorted Personal Papers, 1996-2007 (Box 12-14)
  Correspondence, business cards, and notebooks, arranged by type of material and then chronologically.
  - Reporter's notebooks, 1991-2007 (Folder 12-13)
    - 1991 (Folder 12: 9)
    - 1999-2003 (Folder 12: 10)
    - 2001 (Folder 12: 11)
    - 2002 (Folder 12: 12)
    - 2003 (Folder 12: 13)
    - 2006 (Folder 13: 1)
    - Counterfeiting book, Greek wildfires, 2007 (Folder 13: 2)
    - "Unholy Wars" book (Folder 13: 3)
    - Book ideas, undated (Folder 13: 4)
    - Interviews, 2000-2001 (Folder 13: 5)
    - Various projects, undated (Folder 13: 6-7)
  - Business cards, undated (Folder 14: 1-4)
  - Correspondence (Folder 14)
    - General, 1996-2006 (Folder 14: 5)
    - King Hussein of Jordan, 1989 (Folder 14: 6)
- Miscellaneous Collected Material, 1975-1991 (Box 14-16)
  Brochures, maps, pamphlets, and printed material.
  - American University in Beirut, pamphlets and press releases, 1975 (Folder 14: 7)
  - "Carter-Brezhnev Project," Brown University, 1995-1996 (Folder 14: 8)
  - "Conversations in Lebanon," by Joe and Lois Malone, 1977 (Folder 15: 1)
  - Driss, Rachid, reprints of articles about Tunisia prior to World War II, from Cahiers de Tunisie, 1978-1979 (Folder 15: 2)
  - Environnement économique d'Ossama bin Laden, 2001 (Folder 15: 3)
  - George Polk affair (background material) (Folder 15: 4)
  - "The Great Man Made River Project" (Libyan water pipeline), circa 1980s (Folder 16)
    Oversize.
  - Iraq (unpublished papers and other documents), 1987-1997 (Folder 15: 5)
  - "Israeli Settlement Policies in Occupied Arab Territories," transcript and slides for presentation, from Office of the Crown Prince of Jordan, 1980 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Maps and guides (Folder 15: 7-8)
  - Middle East Peace Conference, Madrid, 1991, "Issues, Facts, and Figures: A Guide" (Folder 15: 9)